Guide to the Northwest Yearly Meeting Administrative Records 1970-1988
George Fox University and Northwest Yearly Meeting of Friends Archives
Northwest Yearly Meeting Administration Records
1970-1988
George Fox University and Northwest Yearly Meeting of Friends Archives 416 North Meridian Street Newberg, Oregon 97132 archives@georgefox.edu http://www.georgefox.edu/offices/murdock/Archives/index.html
Northwest Yearly Meeting of Friends Church
NWYM.01.27
2.5 cubic feet 4 half sized archival boxes, 2 slide boxes (1 slide box also contains other collections)
Records from the administrative offices of the Northwest Yearly Meeting of Friends. Includes records of peacemaking conferences and teaching, Friends Religious and Literary Journal, Family Ministry, Quarterly Meeting Records, Friends Youth Organization record, and minutes from the administrative actions of the Northwest Yearly Meeting, and slides from the Boise Valley Area Meeting, Newberg, and other parts of Oregon.
Item Legacy.365
The Northwest Yearly Meeting of Friends was founded in 1893 based out of Newberg, Oregon. It includes Evangelical Quaker meetings in Oregon, Washington, and Idaho among it's Congregations. The main administrations, the Northwest Yearly Meeting Headquarters, based out of Newberg, is led by a Superintedent. These records contain information about the work of this administrative body and reports made to them by member meetings. It includes records of peacemaking conferences and teaching, Friends Religious and Literary Journal, Family Ministry, Quarterly Meeting Records, Friends Youth Organization record, and minutes from the administrative actions of the Northwest Yearly Meeting, and slides from the Boise Valley Area Meeting, Newberg, and other parts of Oregon.
This collection is available for use.
Pennington, Levi Talbot, Dr.; Ross, Milo
Northwest Yearly Meeting of Friends Church; Quakers; Society of Friends; Peace--Study and teaching
Photographs; Religion
- Quarterly Meeting Records
  - Portland Quarterly Meeting, 1940-1979; 1/1
  - Portland Quarterly Meeting, 1959-1972; 1/2
  - Portland Quarterly Meeting, 1955-1961; 1/3
  - Church Committees N-Z Vol. II, 1984-1986; 1/4
  - Boise Valley Area Friends, 1986-2000; 1/5
  - Boise Valley Area Friends, 1970-1986; 1/6
  - Salem Quarterly Meeting Treasurer's Book, 1890-1944; 2/1
  - Salem Quarterly Meeting, 1954-1958; 2/2
  - Salem Quarterly Meeting Treasurer's Book, 1947-1957; 2/3
  - Salem Quarterly Meeting Cash Book, 1941-1954; 2/4
  - Salem Quarterly Meeting Cash Book, 1954-1958; 2/5
  - Removed from Greenleaf Quarterly Meeting Minutes, 1954-1985; 2/6
  - Greenleaf Quarterly Meeting Minutes, 1954-1985; 2/7
  - Boise Valley Quarterly Meeting, 1906-1931; 2/8
  - Greenleaf Area Rally, 1983-1988; 2/9
  - Puget Sound Area of Friends Churches Area Rallies, 1970-1971; 2/10
- Written Histories
  - Chehalem Quarterly Meeting History by Dorwin E. Smith, 1945; 2/11; Smith, Dorwin E.
  - The History of the Settlement of Friends in Newberg by Genevieve Badley Cole, 1930; 2/12; Cole, Genevieve Badley
  - Salem Quarterly Meeting History by Floyd Bates, 1967; 2/13; Bates, Floyd
  - Why Teach Friends Distinctives? by Dave Votaw, 1993; 2/14; Votaw, David L.
  - Southern Oregon Friends by Milo Ross, 1966; 2/15; Ross, Milo
  - Quaker Faith Relevant? by Cecil Hinshaw, 1959; 2/16; Hinshaw, Cecil F.
  - History of Friends Church in Oregon by John H. Rees, 1906; 2/17; Rees, John H.
  - Remembering 75 Years of History Narration with Parts, 1968; 2/18
- Peacemaking
  - New Call to Peacemaking, 1977-1988; 3/1
  - Peace Committee, 1977-1982; 3/2
  - A Call to Peacemaking - GFC, 1977-1978; 3/3
  - New Call to Peacemaking, 1985-1988; 3/4
  - Peace Conference- GFC, 1977-1978; 3/5
- Friends Religious and Literary Journal, 1985; 3/6
- Family Ministry
  - 1983-1984, 3/7
  - 1982-1983, 3/8
  - 1982-1983, 3/9
- Friends Youth Organization
  - Christian Endeavor Minutes (Exec,), 1959-1962; 2/19
  - Friends Youth Organization and Promotional Materials, 1971-1978; 4/1
  - Friends Youth Organization and Promotional Materials, 1965-1972; 4/2
  - Friends Youth Organization and Promotional Materials, 1959-1965; 4/3
  - Christian Endeavor Officer's Handbook, 4/4
  - Friends Youth Leadership, 1932-1978; 4/5
- Yearly Meeting Corespondence, 6
  - 1974-1980, 4/6
  - 1971-1982, 4/7
  - 1963-1975, 4/8
  - Church Photographs, 4/9
  - Levi Pennington Discipline Revision, 1942; 4/10
- Slides
  Slides containing images of NWYM churches and events. Also containing two slideshows: Who are the Friends? What do Friends Believe?